Guide to the Center for Policy Analysis records, 1987-2006.
Center for Policy Analysis records
- Wong, Arlene K. & Highfill, Clinton A.. Who's at the Table? The Challenge of Fostering Public Participation in Hazardous Waste Decisions - Ten Midwest Case Studies (DRAFT). Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1995., November 1995; Report (Draft) (Box 3, Folder 36)
  Policy issues report draft. 4 chapters plus case studies appendix. 73 pages total
- Women's Voices - Banners From A National Survey of 800 Women and 302 Men. Washington D.C.: Lake Research, 1996., August 5-11, 1996; Research Data (Box 3, Folder 37)
  Compiled book of researched data via survey. Tables, charts, definitions, questionnaire & some handwritten comments
- Ferlauto, Richard, Barbour Arvin, & Shabecoff, Alice. Financing The Future: Innovations in Child Care Financing--Roundtable Report. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1996., August 1996; Roundtable Report (Box 3, Folder 38)
  Policy report on child care financing. 8 sections including intro, the child care financing equation, experiences from the field, case studies, discussions, legislative responses, co-sponsoring orgs & appendix A-B
- Kennedy, John. Technology and the Schools - Preparing the Workforce for the 21st Century. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives & Benton Foundation, 1996., 1996; Conference Report (Box 3, Folder 39)
  Conference Report about CPA & Benton Foundation, Executive summary, 12 sections covering the conference discussions including participant contact info
- Health Care Reports & Seminar Brief. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1996, 97., Various (Box 3, Folder 40)
  November 18, 1996, November 1997, December 7, 1997. 3 health care reports- #1: Purchasing Power in the Health Care Market - Briefing Memo for the W.K. Kellogg Foundation. Seminar.-4 sections 45 pages total (Nov.18, 1996), #2: Health Care in Low-Income Communities- 66 pages (Nov.1997). #3: State Support for Community Health Workers: Community Policy & Leadership Forum. Summit on State Issues- 6 pages (Dec.7, 1997)
- Community-Based Organizations and Telecommunications Industry. Volume 2 - Selected Federal and Private Programs for Technology Assistance. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1998., 1998; Policy Report (Box 3, Folder 41)
  Issue summary including federal programs for technology assistance, private programs for technology assistance & sources of info.
- Policy Memo & Summit Review. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1998., January 9, 1998, December 1998; Policy Memorandum (Box 3, Folder 42)
  2 review packets - #1: Memorandum to SECPLF Members: Southeast Community Policy & Leadership Forum (January 9, 1998). #2: CPA Second Annual Summit on the States - States "In The Money" (CPA president speech, participant contact info & legislation survey)- 20 pages total (Dec.1998)
- Western Policy Leaders Forum, Seattle - Family and Work: An Investment Strategy for Communities. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1999., June 11-13, 1999; Informational Packet (Box 3, Folder 43)
  Photocopy of forum info packet including agenda, participants contact info, various articles
- Women's Voices - Presentation of Findings From a Colorado Statewide Survey. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives and Lifetime Television, 2000., September 2000; Research Data (Box 3, Folder 44)
  Compiled book of researched data via survey. Executive summary,tables, charts, definitions. Analyses of data collected
- Women's Retreat Info. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 2001., Summer 2001; Retreat Materials (Box 3, Folder 45)
  Participant contact info sheet and completed original retreat evaluation forms
- Women's Voices. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1992, 1995, 1996, 1999 & 2000., 1992, 1995, 1996, 1999 & 2000; Issues Materials (Box 3, Folder 46)
  11 documents on Women's Voices events/issues. #1: A Polling Report (1992). #2: Economy Briefing Info Folder (July 16, 1995). #3: The State of the States for Women & Politics - 75th Anniversary of Women's Suffrage in America (1995). #4: State of the States: Women in... (figures & percentages) (1996). #5: The State of the States for Women & Politics: Women Elected Officials (Map. 1996). #6: Women at Work (1995). #7: State of the States: Women & Economic Security (Released Data. July 25, 1996). #8: Women & Economic Security: Remarks by Anne Mosle - Good news bad news ( July 25, 1996). #9: A Challenge to Secure America's Economic Agenda- Media Training Materials (Jan.14, 1999). #10: State Policy Checklist: Investing in Women's Entrepreneurship (2000). #11: Pushing the Boundaries: State Action Improves Women's Economic Lives ( 2000)
- Financial Statements with Accompanying Information. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1987-1990., 1987-1990; Financial Report (Box 3, Folder 47)
  Financial statements, additional information, and report of certified public accountants for CPA. 5 Reports for the years of 1987, 1988, 1989, & 1990
- Steinschneider, Janice. Policy Alternatives on Reproductive Choice. Special Double Edition. Vol.1, Nos. 1 & 2. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1990., January, March 1990; Policy Report (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Public policy reviews on reproductive choice, including newspaper articles, legislative updates & resources
- Steinschneider, Janice & Kim, Nancy. Public Health Solutions to the Problem of Drug Use by Pregnant Women: A Review of the 1991 State Legislative Sessions. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1992., January 1992; Policy Report (Box 4, Folder 5)
  Policy review on solutions to the problem of drug use among pregnant women. Report includes executive summary, statistical data, legislations & alternatives
- Various Authors. Where Are The Progressive Voices? A Short Reader on The Explosion of Radical Right Policy Centers in the States. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1992., November 1992; Reader (Box 4, Folder 6)
  Various newspaper articles on a board range of issues between the conservatives & progressives
- Women's Resource Directory. Statewide Women's Organizing Projects & National Resources. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1993-94., 1993 - 1994; Directory (Box 4, Folder 7)
  Contact Information of resources on Women's issues such as: Women's State Agenda Projects, Commission on the Status of Women, Reproductive Rights Coalitions & National Resources
- Women's Voices. Informational Packets & Policy Report. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1995., January 28-29, July 14, 1995; Informational Packet & Report (Box 4, Folder 8)
  3 women's related informational documents - #1: Women Entrepreneurs: The Economic Champions - Models for Strengthening Women-Owned Businesses (1995). #2: Women's Voices for the Economy: Commission Meeting. January 28-29, 1995. (Folder w/ meeting info, including participant contact info). #3: Women's Voices: Altanta Briefing and Forum. July 14, 1995
- Pomeranz, John. Health Care Briefing Book: Communities and Health Care Conversions. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1997., March 1997; Policy Report (Box 4, Folder 9)
  Policy Study on health care conversions. 4 sections including executive summary, intro, conversion trends, status of regulation & reform proposals, conclusion & bibliography
- Huyser-Honig, Joan. Cooperation Instead of Confrontation: Flemming Fellowships Enhance Legislator's Problem-Solving Skills. Washington D.C.: W.K. Kellogg Foundation, Center for Policy Alternatives, Internation Volume 10, Number 2 -1999., 1999; Article (Box 4, Folder 10)
  Journal article
- Women's Voices 2000. The Most Comprehensive Polling and Research Project on Women's Values and Policy Priorities for the Economy. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives & Lifetime Television, 2000., 2000; Research Data (Box 4, Folder 11)
  Women's project research findings and alternative solutions
- A Progressive Response To The National Crisis. Summit on the States. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 2001., December 8-9, 2001; Pamphlet (Box 4, Folder 12)
  Pamphlet with agenda for Summit
- Local Leaders Mapping Global Issues. Eleanor Roosevelt Global Leadership Institute. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 2001., 2001; Pamphlet (Box 4, Folder 13)
  Information pamphlet on the institution and its framework
- Corporate Leaders Council. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, [no date provided]., Unknown; Pamphlet (Box 4, Folder 14)
  Information pamphlet on the council and its framework
- Various Authors. Taking It To The States. New York: The Nation, 2003, June 9, 2003; Journal (Box 4, Folder 15)
  Original journal including articles by various authors
- Progress In The States: A Report on Proactive, Progressive Victories. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 2004 & 2006., 2004, 2006; Policy Report (Box 4, Folder 16)
  Annual report for the years of 2004 and 2006
- Center for Policy Alternatives Annual Report. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1989, 1991/92, 1993/94, 1995/96, 2001., 2001, 2003, 2005; Annual Report (Box 4, Folder 17)
  CPA's Annual Report - 2001: Strengthening Democracy, State-by-State. Annual Reports 1989-1996.
- Center for Policy Alternatives Awards Dinner. Washington D.C., 2001, 2004, & 2005., 2001, 2003, 2005; Pamphlet (Box 4, Folder 18)
  CPA's Awards Dinner - 2001: Reviving the roots of democracy. 25th Anniversary & 2001 Awards Dinner. Dec.7, 2001.(Invitation included). 2004: Restoring the Promise of America. Dec.10, 2004. 2005: State Leadership for America. Dec.3, 2005
- Horn, Bernie (Ed.). Progressive Agenda: Summit on the States - Moving Ideas to Action. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 2000., 2000; Policy Brief (Box 4, Folder 19)
  Book including policy summaries, reviews, reports, toolkits, resources on 25 issues
- Horn, Bernie & Lindquist, Kirstein (Ed.). 2002 Progressive Agenda: Policy Innovations for the States. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 2002., 2002; Policy Brief (Box 4, Folder 20)
  Book including policy summaries, reviews, reports, toolkits, resources on 53 issues
- Cattaneo, Liz & Horn, Bernie & Lindquist, Kirstein (Ed.). 2003 Progressive Agenda: A Blueprint for the States. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 2003., 2003; Policy Brief (Box 4, Folder 21)
  Book including policy summaries, reviews, reports, toolkits, resources on 50 issues
- Horn, Bernie (Ed.). 2004 Progressive Agenda for the States: Progressive Solutions Built on American Values. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 2003., 2004; Policy Brief (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Horn, Bernie (Ed.). 2005 Progressive Agenda for the States: Restoring the Promise of America. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 2004., 2005; Policy Brief (Box 4, Folder 23)
  Book including policy toolkits & information for 10 core issues
- Horn, Bernie & Balick, Rachel (Ed.). 2006 Progressive Agenda for the States: State Policy Leading America. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 2005., 2006; Policy Brief (Box 4, Folder 24)
  3 items for the 2006 progressive agenda- #1:Book including policy toolkits & information for 11 core issues. #2: Progressive Agenda for Election Reform 2006. #3: Progressive Platform for the States 2006 - Candidate Briefing Book
- Various Authors. Series of State Reports. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, October 1987- January 1995., October 1987-January 1995; Policy Report (Box 4, Folder 25)
  9 original reports of "A State Report On…". #1: Economic Initiatives (Volume 1, Number 3. October 1987). #2: Economic Initiatives w/ Special Report on Economic Conversion (July 1991). #3: Reproductive Choice (Vol.3, No.2. Winter 1992-1993). #4: Voter Participation (Vol.4, No.2. January 1993). #5: Citizen Participation (Vol.5, No.1. July 1993). #6: Reproductive Choice (Vol.4, No.2. Summer 1993). #7: Environment (Vol.11, No.1. June 1994). #8: Women's State Agenda Projects (July 1994). #9: Citizen Participation (Vol.7, No.2. January 1995).
- NPA In The News. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1989-1998., 1989-1998; Media Prints (Box 4, Folder 26)
  7 original prints of "CPA In The News" (newspaper articles & other media info) for the following time periods: #1: Year 1989. #2: May 1993-September 1993. #3: January - April 1994. #4: September - December 1994. #5: December 1994 - March 1995. #6: September to December 1996. #7: November 1997 to April 4, 1998.
- Policy Brief - Moving Ideas to Action. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 2000 & 2002., 2002, 2002; Policy Brief (Box 4, Folder 27)
  6 original prints of "Policy Brief" - #1: Playing Fair: State Action To Lower Prescription Drug Prices (July 2000). #2: Smart Start: Public-Private Partnerships for Quality Child Care (October 2000). #3: Rewarding Work: State EITC's for Working Families (October 2000). #4: Putting TANF Dollars To Work: Support for Working Families (October 2000). #5: Valuing Families: Providing Family Leave Benefits (October 2000). #6: State of the States: Overview of 2002 Oral Health State Legislation (2002).
- Various Authors. Policy Paper - Community Voices. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1999-2000., 1999, 2000; Series (Box 4, Folder 28)
  3 original prints from "Community Voices". #1: Policy Paper - Oral Health For All: Policy for Available, Accessible and Acceptable Care (September 1999). #2: Mental Health Parity: State of the States (2000). #4: Forgotten Policy: An Examination of Mental Health in the U.S. (2000).
- Alternatives - Newsletter of the Center for Policy Alternatives. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1994-2002., 1994, 2002; Newsletter (Box 4, Folder 29)
  18 original prints of CPA's newsletter from May/June 1994 through Winter 2002. (Not all publications within time periods included)
- Issue Forum. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, [no date provided}., Unknown; Issue Forum (Box 4, Folder 30)
  2 original prints of CPA's "Issue Forum" - #1: Electric Utility Deregulation. #2: The Sale and Coversion of Not-for-Profit Hospitals.
- Ways & Means: Reporting on Innovative Approaches to State & Local Government. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1981-1992., 1981-1992; Newsletter (Box 4, Folder 31)
  15 original prints of CPA's "Ways & Means". Publications from January-February 1981 through Summer 1992. (Not all publications within time periods included).
- Women and Health - A WEJC Leadership Brief. Washington D.C.: Women's Economic Justice Center, National Center for Policy Alternatives, 1988 - 1991., 1988-1991; Policy Brief (Box 4, Folder 32)
  5 original prints of "WEJC Leadership Brief". Publications from December 1988 through Spring/Summer 1991. (Not all publications within time period included).
- Business Climate Yields to Growth Climate: The Midwest Pioneers The New Age (DRAFT). Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives with Mt. Auburn Associates, 1987., May 1987; Policy Report (Box 5, Folder 14)
  A Report for the Midwest Leadership Network of the National Center for Policy Alternatives. 5 sections including "the business climate myth", the midwestern states, the states, "state priorities for a new age", etc.- 76 pages
- Stumberg, Robert & Steinschneider, Janice & Elser, George. State Legislative Sourcebook on Family & Medical Leave. Washington D.C: Women's Economic Justice Center, Center for Policy Alternatives, 1989., 1989; Policy Report (Box 5, Folder 15)
  8 sections including intro, overview charts, policy choices, summary of state laws & selected bills, comparison charts, resources & authors
- State Issues Forum. Resource Directory. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1990, 1991, 1992., 1990-1992; Directory (Box 5, Folder 16)
  CPA's publication of the "State Issues Forum- Resource Directory" for the years 1990 through 1992
- Rathbun, Pete. Just Say No: The Role of Material Bans in Integrated Waste Management. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1990., June 1990; Policy Report (Box 5, Folder 17)
  4 sections including executive summary, "the role of bans in solid waste management", "disposal bans", "use bans on plastics", plus appendices & notes - 112 pages
- Totten, Michael. Energywise Options for State and Local Governments - A Policy Compendium. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1990., September 1990; Policy Report (Box 5, Folder 18)
  4 chapters including "energy efficiency", "transportation", "waste reduction", and "renewable energy", plus other options & list of contacts
- Hoskins, Anne E.. Reinvesting in Child Care: Opportunities and Responsibilities for Banks in New York State. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1990., November 1990; Policy Report (Box 5, Folder 19)
  9 chapters including community reinvestment:obligations for child care, implications for the economy, obstacles & risks, managing project & institutional risks, reinvestment approaches for banks, plus appendix & bibliography
- Schrader, Richard. Creating Markets: The Next Step for State Recycling Programs. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1991., January 1991; Policy Report (Box 5, Folder 20)
  4 chapters including executive summary, "spurring demand for recycled products", financial incentives, generating reliable supply, "funding state recycling programs", plus appendices
- Ryan, William. An Ounce of Toxic Pollution Prevention: Rating States' Toxics Use Reduction Laws. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives & National Environmental Law Center, 1991., January 1991; Policy Report (Box 5, Folder 21)
  7 sections including executive summary, intro, background on toxics reduction, evaluating state laws, state ratings, funding for state pollution prevention laws, plus appendices & list of table. (Note: Publication & cover stapled up-side-down)
- Mangum, Kim & Cooper, Jamie & Stumberg, Robert. Voter Purging: The Perils and the Promise. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1991., May 1991; Policy Report (Box 5, Folder 22)
  8 sections including: purging among states, the peril of the purge, the promise of the purge, state options, legal precedents and centralization plus endnotes & appendices
- Cooper, Jamie & others. Policy Alternatives On… - a city report. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1991., May, October 1991; Policy Report (Box 5, Folder 23)
  2 "city reports" - #1: Mayoral Innovations (By Jamie Cooper & Stefania Slaby. May 1991). #2: Youth at Risk (By Jamie Cooper & Marla Greenspon. October 1991).
- Various authors. Reinvesting in Communities: Policy Options for New Jersey. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1991., July 1991; Policy Report (Box 5, Folder 24)
  Policy review for New Jersey. 5 sections including intro, reinvestment agreements, capacity for reinvestment, state policy options & conclusion
- Hoskins, Anne E.. Reinvesting in Child Care. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1991., July 1991; Policy Report (Box 5, Folder 25)
  10 sections including: intro, community reinvestment: obligations for child care, implications for the economy, child care financing, managing project risks & institutional risks, etc. (Update edition from that of November 1990 in Item #19)
- Settina, Nita & Orum, Paul. Making the Difference, Part II: More Uses of Right-To-Know In The Fight Against Toxics. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1991., October 1991; Policy Report (Box 5, Folder 26)
  Report includes executive summary & 10 state case studies
- Cooper, Jamie & Christe, Ian & Nagai, David. Voter Registration and the States: Effective Policy Approaches to Increasing Participation. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1991., November 1991; Policy Report (Box 5, Folder 27)
  7 sections including: intro, election day registration, mail-in registration, motor-voter registration, outreach/access, etc., plus list of contributors & about the authors
- Talbert, Donna (Ed.). The Proceedings of the Family Supports Roundtable - A Project of The Center for Policy Alternatives' Universal Family Agenda. Washington, D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1991., December 1991; Roundtable Report (Box 5, Folder 28)
  Georgetown Law Center. Roundtable review including welcome, intros, agenda, policies & paradigms on family supports, plus appendices
- Herndon, Heather. Ballot Access: Options and Obstacles. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1992., July 1992; Policy Report (Box 5, Folder 29)
  5 sections including: ballot access and the states, arguments for and against ballot access, constitutional decisions and summary, plus appendices
- Cooper, Jamie & Smith, Burck (Ed.). Agenda 1993 - Progressive Policies That Work. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1992., August 1992; Policy Agenda (Box 5, Folder 30)
  8 section agenda including: mission statement, and policy options such as governance, public capital, sustainable development, women's economic & others, on issues such as voter registration, child care, rural revitalization, air pollution, agriculture, toxics, transportation, reproductive choice, plus other programs & staff info
- Eichman, Carole & Ferlauto, Richard & Flood, Marilyn & Stumberg, Bob & Talbert, Donna. Investing in the Future: Child Care Financing Options for the Public and Private Sectors. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives & Child Care Action Campaign, 1992., September 1992; Policy Report (Box 5, Folder 31)
  5 sections including: executive summary, intro, financing & barriers for child care, options plus appendices
- Various authors. Model Legislation Series. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1993., January 16, April 6, 7, 1993; Series (Box 5, Folder 32)
  3 publication series - #1: Rural Intermediary Funding Act (By: Carter Lawson & Robert Stumberg, w/ Lisa Fowler, Larry Calvert & Karen Shiff. January 16, 1993. - Original copy, 17 pages). #2: Campaign Spending Limits Act (By: Ross Yustein. April 6, 1993. - Photocopy, 13 pages). #3: Campaign Contribution Incentive Act (By: Ross Yustein. April 7, 1993. - Photocopy, 7 pages).
- Smith, Burck & Williams, Shelley. Model State Telecommunications Resolutions. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1994, March 29, 1994; Policy Report (Box 5, Folder 33)
  Policy resolutions for telecommunications including: access to the information structure, privacy in the information age, adequacy of information and competition among communication service providers
- Telecommunications & Entrepreneurship in Colorado: Report & Recommendations. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives & Benton Foundation, [no date provided]., Unknown; Policy Report (Box 5, Folder 34)
  4 sections including executive summary, keynote address summaries, voices of entrepreneurs and small group summaries plus appendices
- Smith, Burck & Wagner, Jason. The Southeast Brief: A Comparative overview of voter registration laws in the southeast United States. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1993., 1993-1994; Research Report (Box 5, Folder 35)
  Voter findings review including intro & researched data for 10 southeast states, plus appendices
- "Women's Voices" project materials. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1997-99., 1997-1999; Document (Box 5, Folder 36)